All they wanted was their chance to be men... and he gave it to them.
The Cowboys is a western, adventure, drama film directed by Mark Rydell.
When his cattlemen abandon him for the gold fields, rancher Wil Andersen is forced to take on a collection of
young boys as his cowboys in order to get his herd to market in time to avoid financial disaster.
The boys learn to do a man's job under Andersen's tutelage, however, neither he
nor the boys know that a gang of cattle thieves is stalking them.
Wil Andersen, played by John Wayne.
Jebediah Nightlinger, played by Roscoe Lee Browne.
Long Hair, played by Bruce Dern.
Kate, played by Colleen Dewhurst.
Cowboy Fats, played by Alfred Barker Jr..
Cowboy Dan, played by Nicolas Beauvy.
The Cowboys is a 1972 American Western film starring John Wayne, Roscoe Lee Browne,
and Bruce Dern, and featuring Colleen Dewhurst and Slim Pickens.
It was the feature film debut of Robert Carradine.
Based on the 1971 novel of the same name by William Dale Jennings, the screenplay was written by
Irving Ravetch, Harriet Frank Jr., and Jennings and was directed by Mark Rydell.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
montana, ranch, beef, cattle drive.
The tone is emotional.